Christine Pattee Lesbiana Collection ca. 1970-2000 GLBTQ.2011.02
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
Christine Pattee Lesbiana Collection
ca. 1970-2000
GLBTQ.2011.02
GLBTQ Archives, Central Connecticut State University
6.0 Linear feet
Christine Pattee, a Connecticut native, worked for many years in the Connecticut Health Department. She was a gay rights activist and lobbyist. Ms. Pattee was a founder of the Northeast Women's Musical Retreat (NEWMR). The collection consists of personal papers, records of the NEWMR, books, photographs, T-shirts and other visual materials.
Pattee, Christine
Conditions Governing Access
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical Note
Christine Pattee was a lesbian, feminist and gay rights activist long before these terms were socially acceptable. She lobbied for passage of the first Sexual Orientation Bill in Connecticut (1975), and became known as Connecticut's first gay rights lobbyist. Writing and publishing articles about her experience, she helped to educate gay communities across the country about the obstacles that may be encountered with regard to legislation. As an extension to her activism, she helped to organize several musical events, eventually co-founding the North Eastern Women's Musical Retreat (NEWMR). NEWMR brought women musicians from all over the country to Connecticut for one weekend every September, from its founding as in 1981 to its dissolution in 2000. Ms. Pattee worked as a statistician for the Conn. State Dept of Health, and was also active in health care initiatives for women. She was an avid book collector, collecting rare titles on the topic of lesbian love. Christine Pattee entered college an English major and came out a biologist. After stints as a teacher and Peace Corps volunteer in Ethiopia, she got Masters and Doctoral degrees in public health, and worked for many years in the Connecticut Health Department as a research statistician.
Separated Materials
Books, periodicals, and phonograph records that arrived with the collection are cataloged and stored elsewhere at the Burritt Library.
Scope and Content
The collection of Christine Pattee's personal papers include research articles and monographs on feminism and lesbianism, booksellers' catalogs, and biographical information. Records related to the New England Women’s Music Retreat, photographs, T-Shirts, ephemera and artifacts form the major focus of the collection.
Arrangement
The Collection is arranged into five series:
Series I: Christine Pattee Papers Series II: Records of the North Eastern Women's Music Retreat Series III: Photographic Material Series IV: T-Shirts Series V: Realia and Miscellaneous
Most series are arranged alphabetically by title of folder.
Oral History
An oral history interview of Christine Pattee is available within the Digital Collections of the GLTBQ Archives on the website of the Elihu Burritt Library.
Booksellers and bookselling; Feminism.; Gay community -- Connecticut; Gay couples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States; Gay rights.; Hartford (Conn.) -- History.; Homosexuality -- United States.; Lesbians -- Connecticut; Lesbians -- United States.; Photographs; T-shirts; video recordings; Women's music festivals.; Women's music.
- Series I: Christine Pattee Papers
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I: Christene Pattee Papers contains articles, records of the new England Women’s Music Retreat, booksellers catalogs and articles.
  - Databases and lists of books in collection, 2000-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Catalogs and book lists issued by C.Pattee
    Correspondence to C. Pattee from: Michelle Cliff; Tee A. Corinne
    Yvonne MacManus; Catherine Rule; Celeste Charles; Velma N. Tate
    Karla C. Gipe; Eric Garber; D. Stump; Helen Knupp; Elsa Gidlow
    Carol Seajay, Maureen Brady; Judith McDaniel; Gabrella Nissen
    copy of letter from C. Pattee to editors of Our Bodies Ourselves
  - Lesbiana Want List; Bibliography from University of Michigan (1986), 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Breaking Out, London Feb., Apr., 1981
    Cunningham & Co., Portland, Maine; Q. M. Dabney, Washington, DC, 1974
    Deskins & Greene, Atlantic City, NJ, 1980; Rarities, Chattanooga, TN, 1982
    John Makarewich, Van Nuys, CA, 1980; Paulette Rose, White Plains, 1980-1981
    Second Life Books, Adams, MA, 1980; Joanna Taylor Books, Rancho Cordova, CA, 1982
    Walt Whitman Bookshop; San Francisco, CA, 1980
  - Independent Woman Books (early 1980's) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Beasley Books, Chicago, IL, 1982; Preston C. Beyer, Stratford, CT, 1980
    Boudicca Books, Toronto, 1984; Helen McLean, Brooklyn, NY, 1995, 1996
    Moye Polley Books, Seattle, WA, 1981; Pharos Books, New Haven, CT, 1985
    C. J. Scheiner, Brooklyn, NY 1978-1981; Phyllis Tholin, Evanston, IL, 1983
    Twice Sold Tales, Wellfleet, MA, 1981; Wilder Books, Emhurst, IL, 1981
    Women’s Words Books, Contoocook, NH, 1982
  - Bookseller's Catalogs, 1974-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bookseller's Catalogs, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Naiad Press, Flyers and brochures, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lesbian Publisher’s flyers, booklets A-Z Book Service; Alwin Enterprises; Blazon Books; Bloodroot Collective; Lesbian Voices; New Women’s Times, 1970's - 1980's (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lesbian Herstory Archive News Spring 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Feminist Writing and Publishing edited by Beth Hodges; "Margin" August 1975. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Proof plats from Pierre Louy's La Chanson de Billitis, 1906 (photocopies) with correspondence., April 12, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exercises of teh 23rd Anniversary of the Connecticut Literary Institution, July 30, 1856 (3); with accompanying correspondence dated 1982., 1856; 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence relating to book collecting 1978, 1982-1984, 1999-2002., 1978-2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Words of Women, Hartford Feminist Library, Summer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mystery Scene, #43, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Articles on authors, 1980's (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Literature lists & bibliographies, 1969-1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Books on Homosexuality; Arno Press, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Statement for Conn. Abortion Legislation Hearings May 19, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Women: A Journal of Liberation, Vol. 2:4; 1972, including article by C. Pattee, "Gay and Straight in the Movement". (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sister: New Haven Women's Liberation Newsletter (aka "Connecticut's Feminist Publication"): Vol ii, No.4 (undated); Vol. II, No. 7 (March 1973); Vol. 1, No. 8 (July, 1974); Vol. V, No. 11 (December 1976); Vol. VII, No. 5 (May 1976); Vol. VI, No. 6 (June 1977); Vol. VII, No. 1 (January 1978). Articles by C. Pattee included therein., 1973 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Quest, 1977; photocopy of article, "Death of a Dream" by C. Pattee. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sexual Discrimination Bill: Letters and articles, c. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Women's Agenda, March 1977 "Celebrity Fund Raising", by C. Pattee (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Political Relevance of Lesbianism" (drafts); Women in Hartford, 1982 (newsletter/publication). (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1994, including letter to editor, Hartford Courant. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - “Heroic Deeds and Moral Dilemmas. Reading about women before and after Xena” draft typescript by Christine Pattee, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Douglas College Reunion Book, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letter to C. Pattee from Anne Marcucie, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Letter from C. Pattee to NEWMR Planning Session, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Deedy Breed Obituary, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Women in Revolution (magazine) Summer, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Time (magazine), August 31, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Sing Out (magazine), Jan/Feb 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Political Affairs: Journal of Marxist Thought & Analysis; March, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Smithsonian (magazine); March, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Psychology Today (magazine); July, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Time (magazine); March 20, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Children's Rights, No. 5; May/June, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Women's Sports (magazine); June, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ms. (magazine); November, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ms. (magazine), November, 1977. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Ms. (magazine); December, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Time (magazine); December 5, 1977. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Somerville Community News, Feb. 1978 and Somerville Journal, March 12, 1981., 1978, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Seven Days (magazine), Vol. II, No. 11; July, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Guardian (newspaper), October 10 & 17, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Workers World, Vol. 21, No. 44; November 9, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Quest79, September, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Solidarity: A Socialist Feminist Network (magazine); Spring, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Kalliope: A Journal of Women's Art; 1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Maps of Connecticut Senatorial and Assembly Districts, November 7, 1972 (with annotations by C. Pattee) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Human Rights and Opportunities Hearings (transcripts); Feb. 13 and March 13, 1973. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Sexual Orientation Bill, 1973: responses from legislators (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Resolutions on Sexual Orientation adopted by various groups, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gay Civil Rights Legislation, c. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Gay Rights Lobbying Strategy", (photocopies of manuscript), c. 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "An Act Prohibiting Discrimination on the Basis of Sexual Orientation" Bill 1607, January, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Legislative letters on the Sexual Orientation Bill, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Members of Human Rights and Opportunities Committee that regularly attend meetings; with note from Senator Betty Hudson., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Petitions, Membership Lists regarding the Sexual Orientation Bill, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Notes on legislators with regard to Sexual Orientation Bill, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Human Rights and Opportunities Hearing (transcript); April 3, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Senate debate (transcript) on An Act Prohibiting Discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation; April 16, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - House debate (transcript) on An Act Prohibiting Discrimination on the basisi of sexual orientation; April 23, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sexual Orientation Bill History, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper articles (photocopies) on the Sexual Orientation Bill; 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Relevant letters regarding the Sexual Orientation Bill, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence regarding the Sexual Orientation Bill; 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper articles (photocopies) on the defeat of the Sexual Orientation Bill; 1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence regarding the Sexual Orientation Bill; 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Relevant documents regarding the Sexual Orientation Bill; 1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper articles (photocopies) regarding the Sexual Orientation Bill; 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Articles and information regarding the Sexual Orientation Bill; 1979 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - George W. Henry Foundation. Project “H” Committee Capitol Region Conference of Churches List of Advisory Board Members, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Letter from National Women's Political Caucus, July 9, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Connecticut General Assembly CBIA 1979-1980 Directory (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Connecticut General Assembly Directories (with annotations by C. Pattee);1973-74; 1975-76; 1981-82., 1973, 1975, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - The Complete Cumulative Checklist, 1960, and in the Supplement to the Complete Cumulative Checklist, 1961 / by Marion Zimmer Bradley and Gene Damon;: a listing of lesbian, variant, and homosexual fiction, and selected non-fiction, in English or available in translation, for the use of collectors, students, and librarians (original binder copy), 1960-62 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Wooden sculpture of Loretta Wrobel by C. Pattee, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Flyers on lesbian health issues, 1960-1980(?) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Health Policy Advisory Center Bulletin, March 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Self Help Clinic (newsletter); 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Lesbians and the Health Care System;" (pamphlet) by Radicalesbians Health Collective; 1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Women’s Sexuality Conference (program), May 20, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Donnelly, Mary. "Lesbian Health Care: Issues and Literature (pamphlet); 1978. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hornstein, Frances. "Lesbian Health Care;" 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Robinson, Mina K., "Support Systems for Older Lesbians;" (Paper presented at American Public Health Association Meeting, Detroit, MI); October 20, 1980. and Kolosa-Munro, Lyn, "Sexuality in the Aging Woman;" chapter of Health and Social Work, Vol. 2, No. 4, November 1977., October 20, 1980 and November, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Raphael, Sharon M., Ph.D., "What Health Care Professionals Should Know About Older Lesbians;" (Paper presented at American Public Health Meeting, Detroit, MI); October 20, 1980. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Klein, Paula, "Health Needs Assessment in a Lesbian Community," (pamphlet), Emma Goldman Clinic for Women, Iowa City, Iowa, September 10, 1980. also Klein, Paul and Vilmain, Suzanne, "Self-health for lesbian women;" (brochure); Emma Goldman Clinic for Women, Iowa City, Iowa, 1978, 1978 and 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Lesbian Couples information package on group therapy, with bibliography., undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Johnson, Susan R., M.D., and Guenther, Susan M. Guenther, M.A., "Factors Influencing Lesbian Gynecologic Care: A Preliminary Study; Reprinted from American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Vol. 140, No. 1, p. 20-28, May 1, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Degen, K., and Waitkevicz, H.J., "Lesbian Health Issues" (photocopy) from British Journal of Sexual Medicine; May, 1982. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Thompson Cook, Ann, "Who is Killing Whom?;" Issue Paper: Respect All Youth Project; INSITE and P-FLAG, 1986. also, Thompson Cook, Ann and Pawlowski, Wayne, "Youth and Homosexuality;" Issue Paper: Respect All Youth Project; INSITE and P-FLAG, 1991., 1986 and 1991 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper articles (photocopies) on AIDS and politics, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Infections of the Vagina (pamphlet); Health Organizaing Collective of N.Y. Women's Health and Abortion Project; N.Y.C., n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Socialist Review no. 38 (journal), 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Candidates – 1975 By Christine Pattee and Sandy Vivian
    Transcript of talk presented by Sandy Vivian [14 page typescript]
    Women and Municipal Politics. Schedule of five panel discussions around the state
    “Women’s Political Caucus Analysis Finds Women Have Electorial Edge” press release December 11, 1975
    Zuckerman, Diana M. Psychological Barriers to Women’s Political Leadership” 21p typescript of an article
    Note from the author to Christine Pattee
    Election results chart, January 23, 1976
    Political Caucus Questionaire
    Steering Committee Connecticut Women’s Political Caucus Steering Committee, 1975
    Newspaper articles and correspondence
  - "The Plague;" Committee to Defend the Panther (pamphlet, n.d.), undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Women's Bureau, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Statistics, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Feminist articles (photocopies and pamphlets), 1970's (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Marches on Washington, Nov. 15, 1969;" photocopy of a mock-up of a children's book, undated. (may have been 1979?) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Feminist articles (photocopies, flyers and pamphlets), 1970's (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Feminist articles, flyers and pamphlets, 1970's and 1980's., 1970's-1980's (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Heartroots Fall 1980 [brochure]
    Lesbian Convergence workshops May 1982; December 1983
    Women’s Center meeting to discuss starting a [women’s] center in Hartford October 18, 1977 [flyers]
    Hartford Women’s Center Womanspace Coffeehouse presents Karen Beth [flyers]
    Womyn’s Moonlite Cruise August 20, 1983 [flyer]
    Heartroots, A Feminist Therapy Collective present Lesbian Awareness Series [flyer]
    Trinity and Hartford Women’s Centers present Casselberry-DuPree In Concert, Dec. 10, 1983 [flyer]
    Come Sail Away cruise August 26, 1977 [flyer]
    Women’s Fair at Canton Green, June 23, ___? [flyer]
    Workshop on Eco-Feminism, April 3, ___? [flyer]
    Woman Anger [workshop] February 11, 1979 [flyer]
    Discovering Your Own Space [workshop] January 29, 1978 [flyer]
    Women’s Right of Spring, 7th annual camping weekend May 23, 24, 25,19___ [flyer]
    Women’s Workshop, April 9, 1978 [flyer]
  - Lesbianism articles (photocopies), 1969-1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Student paper on Women's Movement dated Good Friday, 1970. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Freeman, Jo, "How to discriminate Against Women Without Really Trying;" (pamphlet), c. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Socialist Educational Conference, New York, November 26-27, 1971 (flyers), November, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clipping, New York Times Magazine, January 31, 1971. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Announcement/Registration Form
    Program Book
    Map of Retreat site, Mohawk Mountain Ski Area [Flyer]
    Chapin, Gary photographs from the First retreat and a note sent to Christine Pattee, October 14, 1981
    Second: September 3 – 6, 1981
    Announcement / Registration Form
  - Newspaper clipping, New York Times Magazine, March 28, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Notebook
    Minutes, 1992 – 1998
    NEWMR Policies for Festival [9 pages]
    NEWMR Feedback Survey of 1998 Festival November 1, 1998 [4 pages]
    Budgets / Financial Reports, 1990, 1991, 1993, 1997, 1998
    Contract Hartford County 4-H Camp, 1998
    Craftswomen Information Sheet, 1993, 1997
    Telephone Numbers
    Housing Forms
    Greta Holman, contracts and financial difficulties 1997, 1998
    Job descriptions
    NEWMR Bylaws January 6, 1998
  - Abortion Issue in Connecticut (pamphlet), October, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Tobias, S., "Women's Liberation, Phase Two" (pamphlet), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Willson, K., and Transue, Judith, "Report from Lansing;" (regarding New American Movement), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - The Village Voice (incomplete issue), January 4, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Cochran, Heidi and Strasser, Susan, "The Efficient Home: The Technology and Ideology of Housework in the Early 20th Century; (Paper presented at the second annual conference on Marxist Approaches to History, February 23-24, 1974, New Haven, CT. Draft. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Daly, Mary, "The Qualitative Leap Beyond Patriarchal Religion;" (monograph), c.1976 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Lesbian Herstory Archives, June 1975 (newsletter) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Blazing Star (history and program), c. 1975, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Ehrenreich, Barbara, "Socialist Feminism and Revolution", Speech given at the National Socialist/Feminist Conference, Yellow Springs, Ohio, July 4, 1975. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Margy, "Can Lesbians Be Friends?" reprented from Lesibian Connection, Vol. II, Issue 4, August 1976 and Vol. II, Issue 6, November 1976. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "Florida Citrus Boycott Continues"; Gay and Lesbian Coalition of Metropolitan Chicago (flyer, n.d.), undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "Danger on the Right;" Liberation Publications, Inc., 1977. (photocopy of article) also: "Stop Human Rights Abuse Philippines", Committee to Free Mila Aguilar (flyer), n.d., undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper clipping: Des Moines Register, November 28, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Gay Community News, October 14, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Sullivan, Phil, "Teachers: A Scenario Straight Talk About Gay and Straight", Advocate, October 4, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Stegall, Lael, and Crone, Betsy, "Fundraising Events: Making Womanpower Profitable;" National Women's Political Caucus, Reprinted by the Midwest Academy, February, 1978. (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper clippings from the Hartford Courant relating to the Sexual Orientation Bill, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Official Souvenir Program, National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights, October 14, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Stanley, Mary, "Fundraising is Fun;" National Women's Political Caucus, Handbook and Catalog, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Program, The Second Sex -- Thirty Years Later: A Commemorative Conference on Feminist Theory, September 27-29, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Women and Prisons: An outline of a research proposal, by Heidi Cochran, Judy Miller, and Leach Shultz, n.d., undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Heartroots Feminist Therapy Collective flyers (earliest beginning of Hartford Women's Community, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Women and the Corporation: A research proposal by Heidi Cochran, Judy Miller and Leah Shultz, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "Write for your Rights", (brochure), Connecticut Gay Task Force, n.d., undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Program, "Women March to Take Back the Night," July 28, 1979, New Haven, Connecticut (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Women's Center, New Haven, Connecticut: Publications, flyers, pamphlets. 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Women's Weekend (flyer), n.d., undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Newsletter of the Yale Undergraduate Women's Caucus, n.d., undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - New Haven Women's Liberation Reunion correspondence, 2000. (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Yale Break: A Newspaper For and By Women, Vol. 1, No. 2, February 10, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Poems on feminism, lesbianism (collected by C. Pattee), 1960 - 1980's (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Information on radio shows for WMBR in Cambridge, MA; public service announcement script on Women's Day, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Informational brochure from Eugene, Oregon on homosexuality., undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Once Upon A Time There Was a Woman"; (flyer) Lesbian Manifesto, n.d., undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "About Lesbians" (originally designed flyer) n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sutherland, Elizabeth, "Colonized Women: The Chicana" reprinted Liberation Now!, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Elizabeth, "Joys of Lesbianism: A Political Perspective" (photocopy of article), undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - dell'Olio, Anselma, "Divisiveness and Self-destruction in the Women's Movement", n.d., undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Joreen, "Bitch Manifesto", (photocopy), n.d., undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - S.A.G.E. organization brochure, n.d., undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Conditions: A Feminist Magazine (Informational sheets), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Comparisons betwen the Black Movment and the Women's Movement (photocopy of monograph), c. 1973 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous handouts relating to: Day Care Cooperatives, New Women's Series at Unitarian Universalist Church in New Haven; Revolutionary Socialist Feminists -- informational sheet on Radical Women, Seattle, Washington), 1974., 1970's (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Lang, Joel, "Strange Tragedy on Pasture Lane," photocopy of article, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Community Land Trust Handbook (photocopy), 1982 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lesbian Herstory Archives (flyers) 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Geraldine Ferraro (political flyer), 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Hot Wire Journal questionnaire, December, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Articles and flyers on Racism, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Snake Power (magazine), Vol. 1, Issue 2, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Feminist Spiritual Community News Journal, Issue #45, Autumn, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Common Ground: A journal where grassroots women speak from the heart; Vol. VII, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "Unmasking of O" (photocopy) from New Yorker, August 1, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 23)